
<faq>

<group id="group_general">
	<title>General</title>

	<question id="what_is_meanwhile">
	<title>What is Meanwhile?</title>
	<answer>Meanwhile is an open source project for connecting as a client
	to a Lotus Sametime Connect community. There is a stand-alone library
	portion, which can be used to write a client, and there is a Gaim
	protocol plugin which turns Gaim into a Sametime client. There is also
	a significant amount of work into documenting the Sametime protocol.
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="born_free">
	<title>Is this project affiliated with IBM or Lotus?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>No. The Meanwhile project is neither affiliated with, nor
	endorsed or supported by, either IBM or Lotus.</p>
	<p>The project was first available exclusively inside of IBM, due to
	questions of code ownership. These have been resolved, and Meanwhile
	is now open to the world.</p>
	<p>There is still a residual internal project-- with some useful
	IBM-specific features added on-- available from the IBM Intranet at
	<a href="http://w3.opensource.ibm.com/~meanwhile">http://w3.opensource.ibm.com/~meanwhile</a> (note: IBM-only link)
	</p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="where_can_it_run">
	<title>On what platforms can I use Meanwhile?</title>
	<answer>Older versions of Meanwhile has been successfully compiled and
	used on Linux, Win32 (via mingw), and Darwin (Mac OSX). Possibly and
	probably more,	but those are the only ones I've heard of so far.
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="why_no_srpm">
	<title>Why is there no SRPM?</title>
	<answer><p>Primarily because you can make a source-rpm from the release
	tarball with a single command:</p>
	<p><code>rpmbuild -ts [tarball]</code></p>
	</answer>
	</question>
</group>


<group id="group_gaim">
	<title>Plugins</title>

	<question id="what_is_gaim">
	<title>What is Gaim?</title>
	<answer>Gaim is an open source Instant Messaging client platform.
	Gaim supports almost every instant messaging protocol, and any number
	of additional protocols can be added in as modules. It provides a
	single front end for all of a user's various instant messaging accounts
	and buddy lists.</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="case_sensitive">
	<title>Why aren't some of my buddies showing as online?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>It's been noted that the sametime protocol seems to be
	case-sensitive in the identification of its users, unlike virtually
	every other internet identity. Even unlike virtually every use of
	your IBM Intranet User ID.</p>
	<p>Therefore, if your buddy has been entered as 'mybuddy',
	when in fact their ID is 'MyBuddy', sametime will happily
	accept the addition into your buddy list but never provide any status
	updates. You will also encounter confusing problems if they message
	you, as gaim will attempt to reply to the corresponding ID in your
	buddy-list, and sametime's messaging service will erroneously inform
	you that the user you're sending to is not online.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="storage_buddy_list">
	<title>How do I make the Meanwhile Gaim plugin use my server-side
	buddy list?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>Back up your buddy list <i>right now</i> with an official
	client.</p>
	<p>The act of obtaining the server-side list is trivial. Correctly
	parsing the data from it however has turned out to be much more
	complex. Rebuilding that data from what's in your Gaim buddy list and
	saving to the server-side list can be even worse, depending on your
	Sametime deployment. If your deployment is using LDAP style user IDs,
	such as "cn=My Name, o=My Company", then you probably don't want to
	use the Save feature, but the Load feature should be safe. If your
	deployment is using email-addresses such as "myname@mycompany.com",
	then you should be safe for both Loading and Saving.</p>
	<p>The level to which the server side list is used is set in a
	preference attached to the protocol plugin. It has three settings:
	Local Only; Load from Server; Load and Save to Server. The default is
	safely set to Local Only.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>
</group>

</faq>

