
<faq>

<group id="group_general">
	<title>General</title>
	
	<question id="what_is_sametime">
	<title>What is Lotus Sametime?</title>
	<answer>

	<p><a href="http://www.lotus.com/products/lotussametime.nsf/wdocs/homepage">Lotus
	Sametime</a> is a corporate Instant Messaging product sold by
	IBM and Lotus.</p>

	<p>It was originally offered by a company called Ubique as
	Virtual Places (VP), utilizing a client called VPBuddy. The
	protocol and the client application were renamed to Sametime
	when Ubique was purchased by Lotus. Later, the product again
	underwent a name change and is now officially Lotus Instant
	Messenger (LIM).</p>

	<p>The VP protocol is what Meanwhile implements. LIM is slowly
	moving away from VP, instead favoring SIP/SIMPLE as the
	underlying messaging protocol. Hypothetically this means that
	the Meanwhile project will slowly become obsolete.
	Realistically, VP-based deployments of Sametime will probably
	be around for quite a while.</p>

	<p>If anyone has more information on the history of Ubique,
	please let me know via the contact page.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="what_is_meanwhile">
	<title>What is Meanwhile?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Meanwhile is an open source project for connecting as a
	client to a Lotus Sametime Connect community. There is a
	stand-alone library portion, which can be used to write a
	client, there is a Python module wrapping the library, and
	there is a Gaim protocol plugin which turns Gaim into a
	Sametime client. There is also a significant amount of work
	into documenting the Sametime protocol.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="born_free">
	<title>Is this project affiliated with IBM or Lotus?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>No. The Meanwhile project is neither affiliated with, nor
	endorsed, nor supported by, either IBM or Lotus.</p>

	<p>The project was first available exclusively inside of IBM,
	because I didn't want to be sued. This has been resolved with
	Lotus, and Meanwhile is now open to the world.</p>

	<p>To re-cap (because people really seem to have a hard time
	with this one), Meanwhile is not an IBM project. IBM does not
	control Meanwhile.  IBM does not fund Meanwhile. IBM does not
	support Meanwhile. Meanwhile is developed outside of IBM. The
	development of Meanwhile is external to IBM. Inside of IBM is
	not where Meanwhile is developed.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="use_lotus">
	<title>Does Meanwhile use the Lotus toolkit?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>No. It is a project to opperate similarly to the Lotus
	toolkit, but built from extrapolating the binary protocol from
	captured network packets.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="is_it_safe">
	<title>Should I use Meanwhile?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>It's safest to say that Meanwhile is still a beta, and is
	not completely stable. If you are a hobbyist, or some other
	variant of insane person, then go right ahead. Problems should
	be logged in the appropriate trackers with as much pertinent
	information as possible.</p>

	<p>Remember: If it breaks, you get to keep the pieces!</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="where_can_it_run">
	<title>On what platforms can I use Meanwhile?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Meanwhile has been successfully compiled and used on Linux,
	Win32 (via mingw), Solaris, and Darwin (Mac OSX). Possibly and
	probably more, but those are the only ones I've heard of so
	far.</p>

	<p>Wanted: someone to get it to build under OS/2</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="why_no_srpm">
	<title>Why is there no SRPM?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>Primarily because you can make a source-rpm from the
	release tarball with a single command:</p>
	<p><code>rpmbuild -ts [tarball]</code></p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="should_i_package">
	<title>Should I package Meanwhile into my distribution?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Anything from meanwhile 1.0.0 onward should be fine. I would
	not recommend packaging anything before that.</p>
	</answer>
	</question> </group>


<group id="group_gaim">
	<title>Plugins</title>

	<question id="what_is_gaim">
	<title>What is Gaim?</title>
	<answer>

	<p><a href="http://gaim.sf.net/">Gaim</a> is an open source
	Instant Messaging client platform. Gaim supports almost every
	instant messaging protocol, and any number of additional
	protocols can be added in as modules. It provides a single
	front end for all of a user's various instant messaging
	accounts and buddy lists. The Meanwhile plugin for Gaim is
	maintained as part of this project.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	
	<question id="gaim_2">
	<title>Does Meanwhile work with Gaim 2.0.0?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>Gaim 2.0.0 (and later) has merged in the gaim-meanwhile plugin
	directly. Depending on where you get your binaries, you may have
	Meanwhile support automatically. Alternately, you may find a
	gaim-meanwhile package built for that version of Gaim. Either way
	though, you'll likely still need to have a copy of the Meanwhile
	library itself.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="storage_buddy_list">
	<title>How do I make the Meanwhile Gaim plugin use my server-side
	buddy list?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Back up your buddy list <i>right now</i> with an official
	client.</p>

	<p>The act of obtaining the server-side list is
	trivial. Correctly parsing the data from it however has turned
	out to be much more complex.</p>

	<p>The level to which the server side list is used is set in a
	preference attached to the protocol plugin. It has three
	settings: Local Only; Load from Server; Load and Save to
	Server. The default is safely set to Local Only.</p>

	<p>Meanwhile's handling of certain problems with the list
	format mimics the official client, in that any saved aliases
	with the comma (,) character in them will be misinterpreted
	when the list is later loaded. Don't put commas in your buddy
	aliases and you should be fine.
	</p>
	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="nab">
	<title>How do I add a Notes Address Book Group to my buddy
	list?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>Look under Tools&#x2192;Account Options&#x2192;[your
	account]&#x2192;Add Notes Address Book Group</p>
	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="psychic">
	<title>What is &quot;Psychic Mode&quot; and what does it do?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>Psychic Mode is a strange feature. Put simply, it lets you know
	when someone is going to send you an IM <i>before they actually send
	you a message</i>. This is accomplished by opening a conversation
	window/tab when a channel is opened over the IM service from a user.
	Since most clients (including Meanwhile) open the IM channel as soon
	as possible in order to negotiate features, a user of a psychic-enabled
	client will have a conversation window open as soon as someone opens
	a conversation window to them.</p>

	<p>gaim-meanwhile didn't invent this feature. At least two other
	Sametime clients support it, and it was added to this plugin at the
	behest of many switching users.</p>

	<p>"Psychic Mode" can be enabled from the preferences dialog. It is
	disabled by default.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="force_login">
	<title>What does the "Force Login" option do?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>This is an option very few users are likely to need to enable.</p>
	<p>A single Sametime community can be deployed across multiple
	servers, with user accounts configured with a "home" server. When a
	user logs in to a server in the community, its profile is checked for
	that home value. If the home value exists and does not refer to the
	currently used server, the protocol will instruct the connecting
	client to redirect its login attempt to that other server. At this
	point, if the "Force Login" option is enabled, the client will
	instruct the server that it cannot use its home server, and that the
	server should route the connection to the correct home server itself.
	</p>
	<p>The gaim-meanwhile plugin by default will actually attempt to
	open a connection to the home server if it is instructed to. If the
	plugin cannot reach the home server, then it will force the login. In
	some cases, the act of attempting to open a connection to that other
	server may take quite some time before failing. If a user is constantly
	being redirected to a home server they know they can never reach, and
	would like to completely skip attempting to redirect to it, they can
	enable the "Force Login" option.</p>
	<p>"Force Login" can be enabled from the preferences dialog. It is
	disabled by default.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="sneaky_client_id">
	<title>What does the "Hide Client Identity" option do?</title>
	<answer>
	<p>When a Sametime session begins, a 16bit value is sent from the
	client to the server indicating what kind of client it is. Some
	servers are set up by default to only permit clients using the
	"official" values to connect. If you're receiving an error stating
	that you are "Not authorized" when you attempt to connect, try
	enabling this option. Doing so will cause the client to tell the
	server that it is an official client, which will almost always allow
	it to fully connect.</p>
	<p>If you are a Sametime administrator, and would like to know how
	to change the settings for client ID filtering, see this
	<a href="http://www-1.ibm.com/support/docview.wss?uid=swg21114318">IBM Technote</a> on the subject.</p>
	<p>A list of some known client ID values can be found
	<a href="http://meanwhile.sourceforge.net/wiki/Client%20Type%20ID">in the wiki</a>.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="missing_logs">
	<title>I seem to be missing some conversation logs...</title>
	<answer>
	<p>There was a release of the gaim-meanwhile plugin that changed the
	way that Meanwhile accounts were named by appending
	":server.host.name" to the login ID. Since the default loggers in Gaim
	store log files under <code>~/.gaim/logs/meanwhile/[account]/</code>
	all the logs for that release ended up in a different place.</p>
	<p>Version 1.2.0 of the gaim-meanwhile plugin was the only release
	that did this. Version 1.2.1 and later all switched back to naming
	accounts by the login ID alone.</p>
	<p>You can safely copy the contents of the badly-named account
	directory to the correctly named account directly. This will add all
	the conversation logs from the 1.2.0 release to where other releases
	can find them.</p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="rfe">
	<title>Why don't you support ${FEATURE}?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>It's not entirely a matter of not supporting, it's more a
	matter of not <i>yet</i> supporting. Please look through the
	<a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=656721&amp;group_id=110565&amp;func=browse">RFE
	Tracker</a> for features that the project intends to
	eventually provide. If you have something you'd like to add to
	that list, go ahead and do so.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>


	<question id="suse_rpm">
	<title>I'm using SUSE and installed from RPM. Why isn't it working?
	</title>

	<answer>
	<p>SUSE's Gaim installation looks for plugins in
	<code>/opt/gnome/lib/gaim</code>, and the gaim-meanwhile RPM installs
	to <code>/usr/lib/gaim</code>. So all you need to do to get things
	working is:</p>
	<p><code>su -c "ln -s /usr/lib/gaim/libmwgaim.so /opt/gnome/lib/gaim/"</code></p>
	</answer>
	</question>
</group>


<group id="contrib">
	<title>Contributions</title>

	<question id="how_to_help">
	<title>How can I help?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Be supportive! The developer may be very sad, and your
	happy words could turn his day right around!</p>

	<p>In order of precedence, the following are all super
	helpful: protocol insight; patches and bug fixes; bug reports;
	happy thoughts; donations of cold, hard cash</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="protocol_help">
	<title>How can I help with the protocol research?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>The best ways are through <a	href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/libpcap/">libpcap</a>
	packet dumps, and written extrapolation on network antics. It
	may be helpful to have used the Lotus libraries before, but
	that's not necessary. If you notice that an unsupported
	feature seems to generate network traffic whenever you use it,
	capture those packets and explain exactly what you were doing
	to produce them. We'll get this thing figured out yet!</p>

	<p><code>tcpdump -i eth0 -w gaim-meanwhile.capture -s 0 tcp
	port 1533</code></p>

	<p>In the most recent release of the Meanwhile library (in the -doc
	package) there are some code samples. One of these samples is for
	a single-connection, logging, decrypting Sametime proxy (called
	logging-proxy.c) which can be used as an alternative to capturing
	network packets.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="patches">
	<title>Are you accepting patches?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Maybe.</p>

	<p>As with any project, there are apparently arbitrary code
	factors to be taken into account when submitting code. Look
	for the HACKING file in your source tree. If there isn't one,
	wait. I'll get to it eventually.</p>

	<p>Added functionality should not step out of the scope of the
	rest of the file. Services should never co-mingle or require
	one-another. Don't write code that's deployment specific. And
	check your parameters on public interface functions.</p>

	<p>If you're working for Lotus or IBM, it's very doubtful that
	I'll be able to safely incorporate any changes or fixes. You
	may be able to safely communicate the idea/fix, but please
	check with your management first.</p>

	<p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=656720&amp;group_id=110565&amp;func=browse">Patch Tracker</a></p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="bug_reports">
	<title>What's the method for reporting bugs?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>First, ensure that no existing bug report for the same item
	exists before creating a new report. If one does exist, read
	through the commentary. If you feel you still have something
	important to add, then continue on.</p>

	<p>Next, indicate with specificity the nature, demeanor,
	astrological sign, molecular weight, and specific gravity of
	the bug.</p>

	<p>Finally, re-read the report. Check all fields. Is this
	enough information to actually figure out what you're talking
	about? If-- and only if-- you are satisfied that adequate
	information is provided, then submit/update the bug.</p>

	<p>These are all parts of the bug reporting process. Failing
	these steps yet still submitting an item into the tracker is
	not reporting a bug, it's just senseless noise.</p>

	<p><a href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?atid=656718&amp;group_id=110565&amp;func=browse">Bug Tracker</a></p>
	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="attitude">
	<title>How do I keep the developer happy?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>A happy developer wants to solve your problems. He wants to
	help you out, and will take extra time just for you. An
	unhappy developer will instruct you to put sharp things into
	hurtful places on your body, and will then stomp away. In
	order for a project to continue at a good pace, it's important
	to keep the developer(s) happy.</p>

	<p>For the most part, this just means Be Polite. Do not make
	demands.  Don't act threatening or try to wrest control of the
	project away.</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

	<question id="donations">
	<title>Why are you taking peoples' money?</title>
	<answer>

	<p>Because I am broke. Please note that I immediately hand
	over 50% to the <a href="http://eff.org/">EFF</a>. The rest
	will probably buy me toys, or manga, or something.</p>

	<p>If handing over cash isn't your bag, but you still want to
	provide a material reward, there's always my
	<a href="http://del.icio.us/taliesein/wishlist">del.icio.us
	wishlist</a>!</p>

	</answer>
	</question>

</group>

</faq>

